(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T08:54:04.876960",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
やあ、ぼくだよ。
"Hi, it's me."
ぼくのことみんな忘れてないかい？
"Did everyone forget about me?"
みんな！元気？
"Everyone, how are you?"
ときのそらです！
"It's Tokino Sora!"
あ、アンキモって書いてくれてる人がいる。
"Ah, some people are writing 'Ankimon'."
アンキモ久しぶり。そうなんですよ。
"Ankimon, long time no see. That's right,"
久しぶりにね、スタジオで
"for the first time in a while in the studio,"
います！
"here I am!"
皆さんこんにちは！
"Hello everyone!"
ときのそらと、あ、
"It's Tokino Sora and, ah,"
グッドイブニングときのそらです。よろしくお願いします！
"Good evening, Tokino Sora. Nice to meet you!"
今日はね、なんと！
"Today, surprisingly,"
私、3周年です！やったー！
"It's my 3rd anniversary! Yay!"
みんな、始まる前からいっぱいコメントとかプレゼントとかありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
"Thank you all so much for the comments and gifts even before it started! Thank you so much!"
今日はね、あ、ここにも移りましたね。
"Today, ah, it moved here too."
ときのそら3周年ということなので、ぜひね、このハッシュタグでみんな、いっぱい呟いてくれると嬉しいなって思います。
"Since it's Tokino Sora's 3rd anniversary, I'd be so happy if you all tweeted a lot with this hashtag."
みんながいっぱい呟いてくれると私とっても嬉しいな！
"I'd be super happy if you all tweeted a lot!"
そしてね、途中点ね、重大な発表もありますから！ふふっ。
"And also, midway, there will be major announcements too! Hehe."
そっちもね、楽しみにね、待ってもらえると嬉しいなって思います。
"I hope you'll look forward to that as well."
ああ、みんなありがとう！あー、おめでとう！ありがとう！
"Ah, thank you everyone! Ah, congratulations! Thank you!"
いや嬉しい。なんだろ？なんだろな？いや、なんだろだなー
"I'm so happy. What could it be? I wonder what it is..."
もう気になってしょうがないよね、みんな。
"You must be so curious, everyone."
でもまだまだだから。最後まで見てくれると嬉しいね！
"But it's still a bit longer. I'd be happy if you watched until the end!"
なんだろね？楽しみ。そうなんだよ。
"What could it be? I'm excited. That's right."
ということでね、今回はね、なんか、振り返りをね、やっていこうかなって私思ったんですよ。
"So, for this time, I thought I'd do a look back/retrospective segment."
みんなとね、また3年間。3年ってあっという間だな、なんか、早いような遅いようなそんな感じなんだけど。
"With everyone, another 3 years. 3 years goes by in a flash, feels kind of fast yet slow at the same time."
今回は、まあ色々とね、振り返りをやりたかったんですけど、なんか自分でセレクトしたらそれだけで動画が1時間越えてしまいそうになったので、ちょっとそん中からさらに厳選して、ちょっとね、今までのね、私の洋服をね、テーマにね、ちょっと振り返っていこうかなと思ってるので、
"This time, well, I wanted to do various lookbacks, but if I selected them myself, the video alone would probably exceed 1 hour, so I narrowed it down further from those, and thought I'd look back taking my past outfits as a theme, so..."
みんな、いっぱいコメントして、最近知ったよって人は、なんか、あ、こんなこともあったんだねみたいな感じで見てもらえると嬉しいなって思います。
"Everyone, comment a lot, and for those who just found out about me recently, I'd be happy if you looked at it like, 'Ah, so there were things like that too.'"
みんな分かりましたか？
"Did everyone understand?"
あ、振り返りにありがとう。
"Ah, thank you for the lookback."
あ、はーい。あ、やった！
"Ah, yes. Ah, yay!"
もう泣かないで！泣くところにはどこにもなかったから、泣かないでよ！ふふふふっ。
"Don't cry anymore! There was nowhere to cry, so don't cry! Hehe."
そしてね、その後半でいよいよ私、こういう重大発表がありますから、そちらの方も、見逃さないでね！
"And then, in the second half, finally I have such a major announcement, so don't miss that either!"
じゃあね、こうしてね、こう、ずっとここにいてもね、ほら、アンキモ君もね、ちょっとね、なんじゃうから。
"Well then, like this, staying here the whole time, look, Ankimon too, will..."
早速振り返っていきましょう！うわい！
"Let's get right into looking back! Wow!"
はい、というわけでですね、こちらのコーナーでは、
"Yes, so in this corner,"
今までのね、3年間の活動の中から、私がね、選んでね、自分でにこ、あここがいいな、ここがいいなって思いながらこうガチャガチャガチャガチャガチャガチャってお家でちょっと編集した、ときのそらセレクションの名場面とともに、私ときのそらの歴史をね振り返っていこうかなって思ってます。みんな、いいですか？
"from our 3 years of activities so far, I selected them myself going 'Ah, this is good, that's good,' and edited it at home, along with my memorable scenes from Tokino Sora Selection, I thought I'd look back at Tokino Sora's history. Is everyone ready?"
みんな、衣装にもね、注目してもらえるとね、とっても嬉しいなって思います。
"I'd be really happy if you all paid attention to the outfits as well."
それではまずね、もうここにも出てますが、2017年の歴史から見ていきましょう！イェーイ！見ていこう！
"So first, as it already appears here, let's look at the history of 2017! Yay! Let's check it out!"
見えてますか？
Can you see me?
映ってますか？
Is it showing?
はい、ということでね、これが一応最初の私の衣装であり
Yes, so... this is basically my first outfit
初めてのこの...初めてですね。
and my very first... first ever, you know.
はい、初日ですね。めちゃくちゃ緊張してるの。
Yes, it's the very first day. I'm super nervous.
こんばんは、初めまして。
Good evening, nice to meet you.
こりゃあさ、もーさ、あ、初日ですよ、初日。
Man, look at this, oh, it's the first day, the first day!
服はちょっと気合いが入って...あ、ね、ちょっと気合いを入れたつもりでね、
My outfit has a bit of spirit put into— oh, I mean, I intended to put some spirit into it,
今でもそれ着てますから。ちょっとね、柄変わりましたけど。
and I'm still wearing it now. The pattern changed a bit, though.
面白そうだなと思ってライブ配信も初めてみました。
Thinking it looked fun, I tried streaming for the first time.
もう放送事故よ！若いじゃないよ！
Total broadcast accident! I'm not young!
あ、そして、これがね、ちょっと変わった私です。
And, well, this is a slightly different me.
今とさ、結構原型がさ、あるんだけどさ、
Compared to now, a lot of the original form is still there,
服とかも、今とそっくりじゃない？
and even the clothes are almost identical to now, right?
ただ！
Except!
今とね、微妙にね、違う場所があるんですよ。どこだと思う？みんな。
There's a subtle difference from now. Where do you think it is, everyone?
どこだと思う？目の色が違った、そうだね、今はカラコンなのでね。
Where do you think? The eye color is different—that's right, because now I wear colored contacts.
そう、他にもね、服でね、ちょっとね、違うところがあるんだよ。
Right, also, there's something slightly different about the clothes, too.
7回目だよ、7回目。
It's the 7th time, the 7th time!
ベルト、あ、そうそうそう、ベルトも違うね。
Belt—ah, right, right, the belt is different, too.
そう、外ハネすけ、あ！そう！みんなそう、色に注目してもらえるとね、
Right, the outer flip—ah! That's right! Everyone, if you pay attention to the colors,
この今の動画は2017年編となっているんですけど、ニコニコ動画の時代のやつをちょっとまとめたものになります。
This current video is the "2017 edition," but it's a compilation of stuff from the Nico Nico Douga era.
なので、2017年の、まあ、10月ぐらいまでのまとめました。
So, I compiled up until around October 2017.
羽飾り、そう、そうそう、みんなよくわかってる。
Feather ornament—right, right, right, everyone knows well.
そうなの、なんと！ここね、一番このニコニコ時代にも、なんとね、結構色々変わっているところがあるんですよ。
That's right, believe it or not! Here, even during the Nico Nico era, believe it or not, quite a few things changed.
みてみて、ピンクだよ。
Look, look, it's pink.
ピンクだよ、ピンク。ピンクになったの。髪留めの色もここで今のと色合いにてなりました。
It's pink, pink. It turned pink. The color of the hair clip became similar to now in tone here.
今日はハロウィンの放送を身につけて、みんな大好きハロウィン衣装、銀髪ですね。
Today, wearing a Halloween broadcast—everyone's favorite Halloween outfit, silver hair.
ここで、実はアンキモが初登場だったんですよ。
Actually, this was Ankimo's first appearance.
そう、今日は気合が入ってるよ。なんてったってかぼちゃ...かぼちゃ、ありがとうございます。
Right, today I'm all fired up. Because it's pumpkin... pumpkin, thank you very much.
お部屋もさ、ハロウィン仕様になっててすごい可愛くてさ、
And the room became a Halloween version, super cute,
こん時すごいテンションが上がってきたので覚えてますね。
and I remember my tension went way up back then.
まだね、十代だった頃の私。十代だった頃の私。
Back when I was still in my teens. Me when I was in my teens.
うーん、幸せだよね、こんなに素敵な場所。
Yeah, it's happiness, isn't it, such a wonderful place.
こうやってね、Twitterのフォロワー数は...誰もおしゃれね。
Like this, you know, Twitter follower count... everyone is cute.
なんかさ、ここはさ、私的にお気に入りの衣装だから、ちょっと長めに編集しちゃって、これのせいで動画が伸びちゃった感はあるんですよね。
Somehow, you know, since this is my favorite outfit, I edited it a bit too long, and I feel like the video got prolonged because of this.
12人になりました。
We reached 12 people.
そう、この頃はね、Twitterのフォロワーさんが何人ですって毎回言ったり、あ、ハロウィン、おばけと一緒、楽しいもぞ！
Right, around this time, I'd say how many Twitter followers I had every time, and, oh, Halloween, together with a ghost, it's so fun!
ハッピー、ハッピー、ハロウィン、かぼちゃを繰り抜き、飛びじゃう！ハッピー、ハッピー、ハロウィン。
Happy, happy, Halloween, carving out a pumpkin, jumping out! Happy, happy, Halloween.
恥ががあるからさ、絶対恥ずかしいんだもん！
Since there's shame, it's definitely embarrassing!
もう恥を捨てきれてないから、なんか逃げてるもん私。放送をさ、誤魔化して逃げてる、黒歴史だよ、本当に黒歴史だよ。
Since I haven't fully shed my embarrassment, I'm kinda running away. Hiding the broadcast and running away, it's dark history, truly dark history.
アンキモの名前がついに決まるってなってる。
Ankimo's name is finally going to be decided.
ついに決定！ヤツの名前！
Finally decided! That guy's name!
アンキモの名前が決まったかっていうのがあったので、そこがいいんだよ。
There was the question of whether Ankimo's name was decided, so that's what's good about it.
フレッシュさがある。
It has freshness.
待って、今はフレッシュさがないってこと？ちょっとどういうことだろ？
Wait, does that mean there's no freshness now? What does that even mean?
それが余計に可愛い。でもそうだね。
That makes it even cuter. But yeah, that's right.
誰も見ろ、黒歴史じゃないよ。やめてよ！
Everyone look, it's not dark history. Stop it!
黒歴史じゃないから、今ではいい思い出ですから。
It's not dark history, by now it's good memories.
見て、アンキモの名前の候補もこんなにあったんだよ。こんなに届きました。
Look, there were so many name candidates for Ankimo. So many came in.
友人Bとか言ったら面白すぎるよね。
Saying Friend B would be way too funny.
私は困り顔じゃないよ。くまころん。
I'm not having a troubled face. Kumakoron.
空のくま。
Sora's bear.
黒歴史、黒歴史だよ。
Dark history, it's dark history.
私、熊太郎とかいいなと思ってて。
I thought Kumatarou was nice, you know.
男の子なんだと。
Thinking it was a boy.
ポン酢っていうのもさ、ポン酢ってあった。
Ponzu, there was also Ponzu.
あんまり人気のある言葉ではなかったけど、ポン酢ってあった。おっさん。
It wasn't a very popular word, but Ponzu was there. Ossan.
そうなんだ、今のメンバーだったらこん中からアンキモを選ぶのかなって
Right, if it were the current members, I wonder if they'd choose Ankimo from among these...
すごい気になる、あんきも、あんくま、ということでですね。
I'm so curious about Ankimo and Ankuma, so...
進化がすごい、すごいよね。
The evolution is amazing, isn't it?
まずそうだな。
First, let's see.
え、でもなんか当時人気で
Well, back then it was super popular,
あんきもはね、がんあんきもだったんですよ。
and Ankimo was, well, Gangan Ankimo.
からの、あんきもは、そういえば目立たないところに配置されてるんで、そうなの、あんきもそんなに、そう、私は
And then Ankimo, come to think of it, is placed in an inconspicuous spot. That's right, Ankimo isn't... well, I...
あ、懐かしー！こっちやんね、懐かしいよねこのころ！
Ah, nostalgic! Over here, right? It's so nostalgic back then!
九、こんなこともあったんだよ。
9... These things happened too, you know.
七、おっさんかなって。
7... "Ossan," I thought.
六、いやだよ、くまろの名前がおっさんになったら
6... No way, if Kumaro's name became "Ossan,"
ここで22人に増えてる。ありがとうございます！
Here it increased to 22 people. Thank you so much!
ね、おっさんじゃなくてよかった。
Right? I'm glad it wasn't "Ossan."
四、よかったって言わないで！
4... Don't say "I'm glad"!
あんきも奇跡の、どうぞ！
Ankimo's miraculous—go ahead!
ぼくの名前は、もう書いてあるけどね。
My name is already written down, though.
お、お、お、お、お、なん、大体、お
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, what—mostly, oh...
圧倒的なあんきもの、あんきも67.4％やったー！
Overwhelmingly Ankimo, Ankimo at 67.4%! Yay!
ぼくの名前は、ええと、26.3％、でもくま太郎も結構人気あったんだぞ。でも
My name is, um, 26.3%, but Kumaro was quite popular too. But...
ぼくの名前はあんきもで決定したんだ、ここで。
My name was decided to be Ankimo, right here.
君の名前は、君がいない、あんきも覚えてくれるかい？
"Your name is..." You're not here—will you remember Ankimo?
覚えてくれるかいっぱ！そう、君の、君の名前は？
Will you remember?! That's right, what's your name?
あんきもになったよ！
It became Ankimo!
あんきもも今、今よりもさ、ちょっとさ、なんかあんきも動いてる
Ankimo also now, more than now, a bit... like, Ankimo is moving around—
あ、転んだした、やったー！
Ah, he fell down! Yay!
ちょっとさ、あんきもさ、あんきもがアクロバットしてるところ面白かった。あ、ちょっと、なんかあんきも特集みたいなになってるけど、ちょっとあんきもどうしても入れたかったんだ！だって
And sort of, Ankimo, it was funny when Ankimo was doing acrobatics. Ah, it's kind of like an Ankimo special feature now, but I really wanted to include Ankimo! Because...
あれ？いなくなった。
Huh? He disappeared.
キモだったのか、違うの違うの違うの、秋路じゃない、秋路じゃない、キモださなです。キモだよ、キモだよ！
Was it Kimo? No, no, no, not Akiji, not Akiji, it's Kimo-dasana. It's Kimo, it's Kimo!
12月14日の16回目の放送です。サングラスとかつけてみたんかな？キャッチー感ある？そうなんだね、そうなんだね！
December 14th is the 16th broadcast. Did I try wearing sunglasses or something? Has a catchy feel? Is that so, is that so!
いなくなっちゃうの。あ、で、そう、ここで初めての小道具ですよ。
He disappears. Oh, and right, this is our first prop ever.
まあ、まあね、ハロウィンでもあったんだけど、これはね何が起こったかっていうとね、ちょっと帽子をねかぶったら声が出なくなっちゃうっていうね、謎現象が起きて
Well, you know, it was also Halloween, but as for what happened here, when I put on a hat, my voice wouldn't come out—a mysterious phenomenon occurred,
こう無音になるっていうね、ここでねスタジオにクリスマスツリーがね出てきました。ここすごい動いて、あの、あ、声絶対聞こえてないじゃんと思って
and it became completely silent. And here, a Christmas tree appeared in the studio. It moved a lot here, and I thought, "Ah, my voice definitely isn't being heard,"
呪いの帽子じゃない！違うの。なんだけど
It's not a cursed hat! That's not it. But...
なんか、とりあえずなんか喋っていれば聞こえるかなと思ってひたすらね、こう…ゆらゆら、じこじ、じこじゃないよ！
I thought if I just kept talking, maybe they could hear me, so I just... swaying around—Jiko-ji—not Jiko!
じこじゃないよ、でも可愛いでしょう？こういうふうにさ、帽子も被ったことあります。
It's not Jiko! But it's cute, right? Like this, I've worn a hat before too.
おみくじ美味しい？美味しい？今日のおみくじは…
Is the omikuji delicious? Delicious? Today's omikuji is...
おめでとうございます、ありがとうございます！
Congratulations, thank you very much!
声がどっかいっちゃって、そうなの、これどっかいっちゃったからね、ひたすらね動いてね、こうね
My voice went somewhere, that's right, since it went somewhere, I just kept moving like this...
こうやってね、やってね、待ってろ。
Doing it like this, waiting...
事故、事故ではあるよ。ただね
Accident, well it is an accident. But...
頑張ってほらほらほらほら、みんなにね、アップのね、皿ちゃんを見てもらってたんだ。
Do your best, look look look look, you were all looking at a close-up Sara-chan.
どうだい？茶目も可愛いだろ？
How is it? Chame is cute too, right?
茶目も可愛いだろ？
Chame is cute too, right?
ちとみ可愛い、ありがとう！
Chito-mi is cute, thank you!
でもまだ、まだ声は戻ってこないの。
But still, my voice still hasn't come back.
意外と、意外と待ちが長かった。そう、これ
Surprisingly, surprisingly the wait was long. Yeah, this...
こんにちは！あ、ほら、ずっと「こんにちは」って、「こんにちは」って言ってます。
"Konnichiwa!" Ah, look, I keep saying "Konnichiwa," "Konnichiwa!"
語意力が、まじか、聞こえてますか？聞こえてますか？語意力がないですね。今思うと、ない！
Vocabulary power—seriously, can you hear me? Can you hear me? I have no vocabulary power. Looking back now, none!
声聞こえててよかった。こんな感じでですね。
I'm glad my voice could be heard. With that kind of feel...
聞こえてますか？
Can you hear me?
はい、ニコニコ時代にはいろんなことが起こりました。あんきものね名前が決まったりだとか
Yes, many things happened during the Nico Nico era. Things like Ankimo's name getting decided,
実はね、最初の時から衣装もね、その時点で何パターンも変わっていたりだとか
and actually, right from the start, the outfits had already changed through multiple patterns by that point,
やてっ、すごいやって、やててて、本当に
and—wow, seriously—doing that, really...
実は2017年の、そのまだ2017年だけでハプニングになっちゃったのとか、ちょっとなかなか短くしたつもりだったんだけど
actually, in 2017 alone, there were so many happenings that it became a bit of a scramble, and though I intended to make it short,
ポルカちゃんいる？ありがとー！
Is Polka-chan here? Thank you!
ポルカちゃーん、ぱるぱる！
Polka-chan, Palpal!
ね、あ、でも実際ね、同じこと何回も言っちゃうんだよね。手探り感がすごかった。でも
You know, ah, but actually, I end up saying the same thing over and over again. The sense of groping in the dark was intense. But...
みんなで、そのあんきものさ、名前はアンケートちょっとアン、アンケート今を見ると多すぎるんだけど、選ぶの大変じゃんっていっぱいあるんだけど
everyone, as for Ankimo's name, the survey—well, looking at the survey now there are too many, it's hard to choose, there are so many,
決めたりだとかさ、髪、髪型とか
deciding on them, or like, hair, hairstyles, etc.
そうそう、そういうのさ、みんなでみんなからさ
Yeah, yeah, things like that, everyone, together...
こうやってさ、決めていけるのがさ、とっても楽しかったんだよね。
being able to decide things together like this, was a lot of fun.
名前がつくなんて思ってなかったからさ、今では私のレギュラー出演も決まったしね。
I never thought I'd get a name, so by now my regular appearances are set, too.
レギュラー、そ、最初はそんなアンキモ毎回出るって感じではなかったはずなんだけど、あまりに可愛くて
Regular... wait, at first, Ankimo wasn't supposed to appear every single time, but it was so cute...
でも、この子はね、いつもこうレギュラーを取りにこようとしてるから、もうマスコットキャラクターにしてしまおうっていう感じで
but since this child is always trying to grab a regular spot, I felt like, let's just make it a mascot character,
なんか今に至ります。今ではね、なんかいないと寂しい感じもするようなアンキモです。
and that's how we got to where we are now. Now, Ankimo is such that it feels lonely if it's not around.
うんうん。レギュラー
Mhm mhm. Regular...
いや、レギュラーじゃ、ここで、ここでやる時はレギュラーでいるでしょ? ね?
Well, for regulars, when we do it here, you're a regular, right? Right?
でもね、まだまだ続くんですよ。ま、まだね、2017年しか見てないので
But you know, it's still going. Well, since we've only looked at 2017 so far,
次は2018年のやつをね、見に、見に行きたいと思います。
next I'd like to go check out the one from 2018.
それでは、どうぞ!
And now, here it is!
同じクリスマスなんですけど、これは2017年
It's the same Christmas, but this is 2017...
ま、これまでは2017年のクリスマス、ここからが2018年というよりは
Well, up until now it was Christmas 2017, and from here on, rather than 2018,
YouTubeで活動し始めた時の映像になります。あ、お友達のアンキモちゃんも登場します。
it becomes footage from when I first started activities on YouTube. Ah, my friend Ankimo appears too.
クリスマスのはね、袖はないんですけど
For the Christmas one, you see, it doesn't have sleeves,
ほら、アンキモもさ、トナカイになったりして、一緒にね、こうお手入れメイクをしていくわけなんですよ、うんうん。
Look, Ankimo too, like, becoming a reindeer, and together we're doing makeup care, yeah, mhm.
やっぱりさ、ね、袖もある時決まったんだけど、これはないですね。
As expected, right, there were times sleeves were decided, but this one doesn't have them.
なぜかね、ちょっと急にね、たた、戦おうとしてる私とかもね、いるんですけど。あ、そうなんですよ。
Somehow, you know, suddenly, I'm trying to fight or something, there's that too. Ah, that's right.
実はね、この頃はすごいなんかアンキモが
Actually, you know, around this time, Ankimo was...
アンキモが遊ばれてて、あの、もちろん私もね
Ankimo was being played with, um, of course I too...
あの袖のないふりそで着てるんですけど
I'm wearing a furisode without sleeves...
あの、アンキモパンダになったりしましたね。お疲れ様でした。
Um, it became an Ankimo panda and stuff. Good work to us.
そしてこれが、なかなか珍しい、えっと「ミラティブQ」っていうね、初めての司会の後での、アフタートークです。緊張しすぎてね、声がね、ふぁわふぁわなんですけども。
And this is quite rare, um, after-talk following my first hosting gig called "Mirrativ Q". I was so nervous that my voice was all jittery.
これ今のお部屋にもある帽子だよね。懐かしいねー。顔が映ってて
This is a hat that's also in my room now, right? So nostalgic. My face is reflected...
そう、初めての司会だったから、本当に緊張してこれよく見るとさ、衣装見て、衣装見て、なんかさ、ギラギラになってんの、衣装ラメになってて
Right, since it was my first hosting gig, I was really nervous. If you look closely, look at the outfit, look at the outfit, it's sparkly, the outfit has glitter on it.
頑張れたよかったです。
I'm glad I managed my best.
すごいなんか、クイズ、これは重要、なんかいない。なんで泣くの?
Wow, like, quiz, this is important, somehow not there. Why are you crying?
あ、今日は、お世話になってる、ここで初めての長袖です。でも、あるから
Ah, today, I'm being looked after, this is my first time wearing long sleeves here. But since there are some...
これはですね、バレンタインですね。いつも応援ありがとう。
This is, you know, Valentine's. Thank you for always supporting me.
それがあるの、あるんです。わざわざ最初からいてくれて、待っててくれて。
It's there, it really is. Going out of your way to be there from the start, waiting for me.
シックって感じで可愛いじゃん。まあ、こんなシックいつもきてるんですけどね。
It's cute in a chic way, right? Well, I always wear chic things like this though.
袖なんていらない。いるよ!
I don't need sleeves. You do!
そう、皆さん、元気?
Yeah, everyone, how are you?
久しぶりの袖だよ。やっと袖がついたんだな。
It's been a while since I had sleeves. Sleeves finally attached, huh.
かわいいじゃん! 私の大好きなさ、ピンクの服をさ、着てもらって、着てもらってる。嬉しいというかね、服を
Ain't it cute! Wearing my favorite pink clothes, you're wearing them for me. I'm happy, or rather, the clothes...
エーちゃんでは、なくてですね。
E-chan... well, no, it's not.
ね、やっぱさ、こういうガールにいなくってさ、冬になると着たくなくなっちゃうんだよね。
Right, as expected, when you're not a gal like this, when winter comes you stop wanting to wear them.
この時はね、アンキモが待ってて、アンキモが待っててくれて
At this time, you know, Ankimo was waiting, Ankimo was waiting for me...
連れてきました。一番のアンキモ。チョコレートアンキモです。
I brought it. The number one Ankimo. It's chocolate Ankimo.
見て、カメラマン、ちょっと黒い。チョコレートアンキモ
Look, cameraman, a bit black. Chocolate Ankimo
そして、最近はね、見かけなくなりましたが、私実はね、普段メガネかけてることもありまして
And, lately you don't see it much, but actually, I sometimes wear glasses usually,
こうやってね、ハート飛んでるっていう感じなんですけど
like this, hearts are flying around,
メガネをね、付けたりしたりした時もありましたね。
there were times when I wore glasses and stuff too.
アンキモを待ってるのはもうデフォルトです。いつもです。
Waiting for Ankimo is already the default. Always.
そして、ネコミミ! 今こう見るとさ、なんか小物すごいパーカ、この肉球が好きなのよ。
And, cat ears! Looking at it now, like, the accessories, the hoodie, I love these paw pads.
ね、懐かしい。2月の22日、ネコの日っていう人がいるんで、サンキューサンキュー。
Right, nostalgic. February 22nd, some people call it Cat Day, so thank you thank you.
見ててください。ここら辺から見てた人もいるのかな。なんか2018年ぐらいからね、見てくれてる人も増えてきている感じが
Please watch. I wonder if there were people watching from around here. It feels like starting around 2018, the people watching have been increasing.
ありましたからね、
Since it was there,
ここら辺でしたってしても結構ね、いるんじゃないかなと思います。
even if someone knew it was around here, I think there are quite a few.
ちょっとちょっと斜めってる
It's a little, a little slanted.
マッチ売りの少女
The Little Match Girl.
電球、気にしない方向でね。はい。
The lightbulb... let's ignore that. Yes.
ねこやんけ。
It's a cat!
あ、顔が埋まってる気がする。
Ah, I feel like my face is buried.
そう、顔が埋まってるんですよ。
Yeah, my face is buried.
ほら、せーの、で、じゃっかりこ…じゃっかりこ言っちゃった。
Look, ready, set—jakkariko... I said jakkariko.
その間違えてじゃっかりこって言っちゃったのがさ、そのまま編集で残ってて
That mistake where I said 'jakkariko' stayed in the edit just like that,
ハッピハッピニャンニャン、にゃんこの日ー！！
Happy Happy Nyan Nyan, Cat Day!!
これはね、今だと響けおちゃがで、すごいね、すぎ、すごい好きって言ってくれることが多いやつですね。クリスマスからだな。
Nowadays, people often say they really love it. It's been since Christmas.
やっぱ、そっか、そこら辺からか、新鮮？あ、今日知った。そうなんですよ。
Right, from around then, huh? Fresh? Ah, I just learned that today. That's right.
意外とね、こういう感じでね、色々とやってます。
Surprisingly, I do various things like this.
バースデー！っていうか
Birthday! Or rather,
みんながバースデーって言ってくれるの
everyone wishing me a happy birthday,
の期待してね、ハッシュタグ、ときのそらお誕生日
expecting that, with the hashtag #TokinoSoraBirthday,
だいぶ2018年になると、この衣装も今とね、すごいね、似てる感じですね。
By 2018, this outfit feels very similar to now.
あ、ほぼ一緒ですね、ここは。
Ah, it's almost the same here.
まだね、一生懸命、あ、よりまに近くなった。
Still, I tried hard—ah, it got closer to Yorima.
そうそうそう、ここら辺からね、私のね、18ぐらいなので、2018年って18歳、もうね、年齢もわかんない。
Right, right, from around here, I'm around 18, so in 2018 I was 18—well, I don't even know my age anymore.
そのぐらいになるとね、やっぱね、雰囲気もね、同じようになってきますよね。
When you reach around that age, the vibe starts to become similar, right?
高校生とさ、高校卒業頃だとさ、ちょっと雰囲気違うじゃん。
High schoolers versus around high school graduation have a slightly different vibe.
今よりも幼い。
Younger than now.
それはそう、10代だもん。もうね、数えるのもわかんなくなってくるの。
Well yeah, I was in my teens. You lose track of counting.
周りの環境だけは最強。これが私の自慢なので、こんなふうに
Only the environment around me is the strongest. That's my pride, so like this,
周りにね恵まれて、今の方が幼い、どういうこと？
Blessed by those around me—wait, I'm younger now? What does that mean?
幼くないよ！
I'm not young!
こうやってみんなからお誕生日おめでとうって、お祝いしてもらえた分、たくさん
As much as everyone celebrated my birthday like this, a lot—
髪の色がまだ明るい。
My hair color is still bright.
そうだね、今よりも髪は明るめだよね。
That's right, my hair was brighter than it is now.
というわけでですね、
And so,
私からの告知です。
an announcement from me.
5月26日(土)の20時から
On Saturday, May 26th, from 8 PM,
若さが隠れないね。
My youth can't be hidden.
ということ、若さって驚いていくのちょっとやだよ。感謝祭というのを
I hate being startled by youth like that—we're holding a Thanksgiving festival.
2020年から知りました。ありがとうございます！一緒にしてくれたみんなも嬉しいです。ありがとう！
I learned about it from 2020. Thank you! I'm happy for everyone who celebrated with me too. Thank you!
間違い探ししよう。何の間違い探しすんの？ほぼ一緒だよ。
Let's play spot-the-difference. What difference are we spotting? They're almost the same.
変わってないでしょ？初々しいです。
Hasn't changed, right? It's so fresh.
たくさんの、お祝いをね
With lots of celebrations,
本当にありがとうございます。こうしてねもらってばっかりじゃなくて、それを返せるように、これからもともだめいぞうで頑張って
thank you so much. Not just receiving like this, but so I can return it, I'll keep doing my best as Tomodameizo—
リボン、そう、リボンがね、ちょっと、ザシュッて今度は、ピョンって感じになってますね。
The ribbon, right, the ribbon is kind of—slash, this time it became like a 'boing' feel.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日は、今日はクリスマスだよ。あんことも仲良くなりました。
Today is, today is Christmas. We've become good friends with Anko too.
あ、私の足、あ、あ、私のお尻、可愛い。本当にかわいい。
Ah, my feet—ah, ah, my butt is cute. So cute.
あ、開け忘れた。早すぎる。
Ah, I forgot to open it. Way too fast.
え、かわいいんだけど。え、あんこともこんなに、私にはおもちゃつけられないの。
Eh, so cute. Eh, even Anko—I can't put toys on myself like that.
あんこともばっかりいっぱいおもちゃあるじゃん。ずるいじゃ。
Anko has so many toys. No fair.
というわけでね、2018年の
And so, looking mainly at 2018's
衣装をメインに見てきました。どうですか？
outfits—how was it?
気になる、鼻、鼻がついてるの気になる。
I'm curious, the nose—I'm curious about the nose attached.
あんことも久しぶり。あ、なくなった！
Long time no see, Anko. Ah, it's gone!
なくなってる。呪いの帽子？
It's gone. A cursed hat?
ぜん呪われてないの。2018年は、だから、袖のない服を切れるようになったりとか、なんか
It's not cursed at all. In 2018, I became able to wear sleeveless clothes, and like,
ちょっとね、今のこの衣装にね、近づいてる感じとかもあって、ま、そこまでね、そんなに大きくね、変わった感じはね、
it feels a bit closer to this current outfit, so, well, it hasn't changed all that dramatically,
ないんじゃないでしょうか、皆さん。でも、でもね、結構マイナーチェンジはしてるでしょ？
don't you think, everyone? But, but, you know, we've made quite a few minor changes, right?
お洋服のこうヒラヒラさとか。だから、意外とね、衣装をね、
Like the flutteriness of the clothes. So, surprisingly, the outfits,
1年ごとにちょっと変わってるんですよ。
they change a little bit every year.
なんでまた、なんでまたそれなくなったの。これは私の1丁羅です。
Why did that go away again? This is my one and only fine outfit.
スタジオの中はさ、あったかいからさ、だから、別に、こう
Inside the studio, you see, it's warm, so, therefore, not really, like—
してつけなくても全然問題ないんですよ。
Even if I don't wear it, it's totally fine.
夏でも冬でも
Whether it's summer or winter,
スタジオはいい快適な温度だから
the studio is at a nice, comfortable temperature,
別に袖がなくても
so even if I don't have sleeves—
袖がなくても
even without sleeves—
いいんです。
it's totally fine.
袖、ここぐらいまで？
Sleeves, like up to here?
ね？
Right?
くるぶし か。
Ankles, huh?
2回行ったじゃないよ。
I didn't say twice!
あ、ニコ生時代から見てま…ありがとうございます、すごい。
Ah, you've been watching since the NicoNama days... Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます。最近の方も、あ、楽しめてますか？
Thank you! Are newer fans enjoying it too?
エンジョイ？エンジョイ？
Enjoying? Enjoying?
どうですか？こう振り返って来てみてるんですけど、結構楽しめてますかね、みんな。
How is it? Looking back like this, I wonder if everyone's enjoying it.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
小さなクマかわいいでしょ。かわいいでしょ。
The little bear is cute, right? Right?
同じ動きしてくれるの。
It copies my movements.
あ、イエス、サンキュー！
Ah, yes, thank you!
そして、これは本当に最新ですね。最後2019年編を見ていきましょう。
And this is truly the latest one. Let's finally look at the 2019 segment.
どうぞ！
Here we go!
そらとものみんなー、元気ー？
Sora-tomo everyone, how are you?
ということで、2018年のクリスマスです。
So that was Christmas 2018.
クリスマスで区切っちゃったから、2019年編なんだけど、2018年のクリスマスあります。
Since we cut it off at Christmas, this is the 2019 section, but there's Christmas 2018.
疲れた～
I'm tired~
もうプレゼントないでしょ？全部配ったの～！！
No more presents left? I handed them all out!!
この時のね、クリスマス衣装を見ると、ここがふわふわになってたりしてね、ちょっとかわいいでしょ。
Looking at the Christmas outfit from back then, this part is all fluffy, which is kind of cute, right?
まだプレゼント残ってるじゃん！！でも宛先がない…
There are still presents left!! But there's no address written...
企画の中のから持ってきたからネタ感がすごいんですけど
I brought this from inside a project, so the gag factor is strong, but...
ほら！振り袖あったの！袖が増えました！ついてはないんですけど、でも袖はありますね。
Look! There was a long-sleeved kimono! The sleeves increased! They aren't attached, but the sleeves are there.
クソじゃないよ。
That's not crap!
はいというわけで
So, with that...
ちぐはぐ感っ子して
with that mismatched vibe...
メジャーデビュー
Major debut...
何が見せたかったかっていうと、後ろの暗号が巨大だよっていう
What I wanted to show you is that the cipher in the back is huge!
こういうのが初めて出たときがあって、ほら、吉とか占いになっててさ。それがね、なんか、私すごいこの暗号がさ、ボーン！
There was a time when something like this came out for the first time, see, it's fortunes and divination. I really loved how this cipher just boom!
ボンって出てくるのが好きで、これすごい気に入ってたんですよね。
popped right out, I really liked it.
だから、暗号の本体は寝てるけど、後ろの暗号はちゃんと占いをしてくれてると思って。
So, I thought even though the main body of the cipher is sleeping, the cipher in the back is properly doing fortune-telling for us.
また待ってる。そしてこれが
Still waiting. And this is...
バレンタインのときの私の衣装です。ときのそらです。
My Valentine's outfit. I'm Tokino Sora.
見て、ハートもぴょんって出るしさ、コートもやってきますよ。
Look, hearts pop out, and coats come in too.
なんかちょっとさ、雲もさ、大人っぽくなってるでしょ？袖あるから。これはセーフ。
And the clouds look a bit more mature, right? Because there are sleeves. This is safe.
よろしくお願いします。そう、今日はねバレンタイン生放送ということで、見て！
Please look forward to it. Right, today is a Valentine's live broadcast, so look!
ねえ、私この衣装大好きで、もう嬉しくてずっとこれ着てたかったの。これ普段の衣装でいいじゃんみたいな。
Hey, I love this outfit so much, I was so happy and wanted to keep wearing it. Like, why can't this be my regular outfit?
そう、今日ね
Yeah, today...
帽子もかわいいでしょ？私あんまりさ、こう帽子とかさ、頭の小道具ってさ、ないからさ、帽子嬉しかったりするんだよね、かぶりもの。
The hat is cute too, right? I don't usually have hats or head props like that, so I get really happy about hats and headwear.
お姉さんって呼んでね♪しなやかな動き
Call me older sister. Graceful movements...
止まらねえぞ～♪
There's no stopping us~
ねんねして行くってどういう事？ねんねんねんね、これ。
What do you mean by going to sleep? Sleeping, sleeping, this.
これです。私のねんね、これ。そして
This is it. My sleeping, this. And...
どうなんですかよ。これ見てください。1つ目のお知らせ。
What is it? Please look at this. The first announcement.
そう、去年だな。そうだよね。お化粧がやっと自分でちゃんとできるようになった
Yeah, that was last year. That's right. I finally learned how to do my own makeup properly.
去年ね、お化粧会です。やった！あんきも1人だけいる。こんなポーズも、こんなポーズもできちゃいます。
Last year was the makeup party. Yay! Only Ankimo is here. I can do poses like this and like that too.
この時からね、私お化粧上手になってね、こんな感じでね、いっぱいさあさあねるようになる
From this time on, I got good at makeup, and like this, I started sleeping more and more...
今の感じ、今ですから。
That's how it is right now, today.
ほら！えーちゃんもここでさ、ほら、あ、でも私がみせたかったのはこの…
Look! A-chan is right here too, see—ah, but what I wanted to show was this...
この「うー」が好きなんで
I love this "oo" sound, so...
そして、ここであんきもがDJになりました。開催決定で～す！
And here, Ankimo became a DJ. It's been decided!
えまめ、そう、えーちゃんもいる。この回はね
Emame, right, A-chan is there too. In this episode...
ほら、ちゃんと色塗った巨大えーちゃんもいるんだよ。すごいじゃん、私。画力も上がってる。3年間で画力も上がりましたね！
Look, there's even a huge colored A-chan. Amazing, right? My drawing skills have improved too. My drawing skills really improved in 3 years!
DJあんきももいて…泣くじゃないよ！
DJ Ankimo is here too... Don't cry!
はははじゃないよ！
It's not "haha"!
なんでみんなはははって言ってんの？
Why is everyone going "haha"?
そしてこれがね
And this here...
見て下さいよ、夏の水着！
Look at this, my summer swimsuit!
え、なんで水着隠してるのかって？
Eh, why am I hiding my swimsuit?
え、そうだな、なんで火力に対してだけ、
Well, let's see, why won't you say "hm"
なんてうんって言ってくれないの？
just to my firepower going up?
マインクラフトとか遊びに来るなんて初めてだからさ
Because it was my first time coming over to play Minecraft.
ホロライブサマーということでね、水着以上ですよ、どうですか？
For Hololive Summer, it's beyond a swimsuit, what do you think?
めちゃくちゃかわいいな
It's super cute.
これやばすぎた！これ以上ね、すごい好きだったの
This was too crazy! I loved it even more than this!
アンキモも水着じゃない、いやアンキモは水着なくても着れるから
Ankimo doesn't have a swimsuit either—well, Ankimo can wear things without one.
みんなの心をはればれ元気にするときのそらです！
To cheer up everyone's hearts, it's Tokino Sora!
あ、この頃から見てくれた？
Ah, did you watch from around this time?
これ何だと思う？今見てもみんな分かるでしょ？
What do you think this is? Even seeing it now, everyone knows, right?
なんでしょう、このポーズ、なんでしょう
What could this pose be? What could it be?
とてもよい、ありがとうございます
Very good, thank you very much.
バレーじゃないんだな
It's not volleyball!
あ、アテネのスタイル！
Ah, the Athenian style!
こっちだ！バナナボートでした！
This way! It was a banana boat!
バナナボートにのってたし私に見えたでしょみんな！バランスボールじゃない
You all saw me riding the banana boat! Not a balance ball!
なんて海でバランスボール乗らなきゃいけないんだろ
Why do I have to ride a balance ball in the sea?
カエルじゃないよ！
It's not a frog!
あと、私は泳げないんですよう、だから
Also, I can't swim, so...
はしゃぎ方が完全に子供、ちょっと
The way she gets excited is totally like a child, wait...
ほら見て、浮き輪、浮き輪をね、もらいました
Look, see? I got a swimming ring, a swimming ring!
浮き輪がないと私泳げないので、浮き輪があるおかげでね、海入れましたね
Without a swimming ring I can't swim, so thanks to it, I got into the ocean.
よかったです。あ、足ついてる
I'm glad. Ah, my feet are touching.
足ついてるって言わないでよ！
Don't say my feet are touching!
球技じゃないから
It's not a ball game!
でも、必ずになんですよね、全然泳げなくてだから海行ってもね
But it's a must, I really can't swim, so even if I go to the beach...
全然浮き輪の気したから全然ダメなんですよ
I used the swimming ring so it's totally no good.
戻ろう。
Let's go back.
ちょ、待って。待って。
Wait a minute. Wait.
なんだなんだこの衣装、なんだなんだなんだなんだ
What, what is this outfit? What what what what?
僕どうなってるの？頭になんか、バランスボールかなこれわ？
What's happening to me? Something on my head... is this a balance ball?
エダマメクッション、ほしいな
Edamame cushion, I want one.
なんだこの絵面！おもしろ！何これ？規制してる
What is this visual! So funny! What is this? It's restricted!
えこ、でも、これが私たちなんですよ、この3人で
Ehh, but, this is us, the three of us...
今まで、スイカ、季節感もおかしくないですかちょっと、季節感の
Up until now, watermelon, isn't the sense of season a bit weird?
冬に、冬に、夏にえーちゃんっていう、えーちゃんはちょっと季節関係ないけど
In winter, winter, in summer, E-chan—well, E-chan's season doesn't really matter.
あ、あ、あ、出来てる出来てる
Ah, ah, ah, it's working, it's working.
割れた！
It broke!
あれ？戻ってる。一瞬で戻った。
Huh? It's back. It went back in an instant.
頭で割りましたね。頭で、あの
You broke it with your head. With your head, um...
スイカは頭で割るものでした。みんな覚えておきましょう。
Watermelons were meant to be broken with the head. Everyone remember that.
どうでしたか？ということでね、一応、あの衣装だけにこうこだわって、私自分でこう時のそらセレクションということでやったんですけども
How was it? So, keeping to just the outfits, I curated this as "Tokino Sora's Selection"...
いい感じでしたかね？クレイジーって言わないで
Was it a good vibe? Don't call it crazy!
幻覚かな？
Is it a hallucination?
そう、頭で割りますよ、頭で。パワフル、パワフルでしょ？あ、いい感じになった？
That's right, you break it with your head. Powerful, isn't it? Ah, did it turn out nice?
あ、楽しかったよかった！今日はね、あの初めてましての人もいっぱいいると思ったので、ちょっと衣装にこう合わせて、こう今までの私を知ってもらおうかなって思ったんですけど
Ah, I'm glad it was fun! Today, I thought there might be a lot of people meeting me for the first time, so I matched it with my outfits to let you know more about me up until now...
最近知った人は今までの私こう、分かりましたかね？だんだん大人っぽくなってる私がね、ちょっとね分かると思うんですけど
For those who recently got to know me, did you understand how I was until now? I think you can tell I'm gradually becoming more adult-like.
どうですか？私、ちゃんと大人っぽくね、成長してると思うんですけど、いい感じですよね？うんうんうんうん。
How is it? I think I'm growing up properly to be an adult, don't you think it has a good vibe? Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
いや、やっぱね、3年も経てば私も立派な大人になるわけですよ。
Well, after 3 years, I become a fine adult, after all.
半袖じゃあ女子力、あ、そういえばあったな、そんな感じに、うん、そう、そうだね、うん。
Short sleeves, feminine charm—ah, come to mention it, there was that, right, yeah.
ん？なんでみ、ん？うんうん、あ、うんだってこうしてる人もいるからね、そうだね。そうですよ！
Hmm? Why ev-, hmm? Yeah yeah, ah, yeah because there are people doing that too, right. That's right!
というわけでね、本当に何かあっという間の3年間
And with that, truly, what felt like a flash of 3 years...
だったんですけど
was, but
ねえ、ここまできね
you know, coming this far
こんな楽しく活動してこれたのはね
and being able to have this much fun doing activities
今見てるみんなのおかげなので
is thanks to all of you watching right now,
もう本当にね、ありがとうございます。
so really, thank you so much.
とっても嬉しいです。
I'm so happy.
でね、みんな今日重大発表があるって言ったでしょ?
And you know, I said there's a big announcement today, right?
みんなにね、見せたいものがあるんですよ。
There's something I want to show you all.
ということでね、今日の重大発表はこちらです!
So, today's big announcement is right here!
私、新しいお化粧を
I've learned...
覚えましたー!
a new makeup style!
イエーイ!
Yay!
そうなんですよ。新しいお化粧を覚えてね、より私大人っぽくなって
That's right. Learning a new makeup style, I want to become a bit more adult-like...
行こうかななんて思ってます。
or so I think.
ちょっとね、構想の途中なんですが
Wait, it's still in the conceptual stage, but
今からね、ちょっと化粧をし直して、衣装も変えれるので
from now on, I'm going to redo my makeup and change my outfit,
ちょっと着替えとね、化粧があるので
so since I have to change and do my makeup,
ちょっと、ちょっとね、あのちょっと今からちょっと待っててもらいたいんですが大丈夫ですか?みなさん。
um, could you wait for me for a bit? Is that okay, everyone?
あんきもじゃない、あんきもがまさかじゃないんだ、ちょっと。あんきもじゃない。
Wait, not Ankimo—wait, it's not Ankimo, right?
私、私、いつか僕もお洋服もらえるのかな? お洋服より出番が欲しいな、あんきもです。
"I wonder if I'll ever get new clothes too? I want more screen time than clothes, I'm Ankimo."
はい、というわけでおめかしをしてくるので
Right, so since I'll be dressing up,
ちょっと待っててね!わあ!
please wait for me! Yay!
はい、というわけでね、今お化粧中です。着替えもね、してますよ。
Right, so I'm currently doing my makeup. I'm changing too.
でと、でも、こう待ってる間さ、ずっとさこのさサムネだと言ってつまらないと思うので、ちょっとね、喋りながらね着替えてね、いこうかなと思いますよ。
But, while waiting, I thought it'd be boring just looking at this thumbnail, so I thought I'd chat a bit while changing.
お、これなんか、やっぱいい感じだね、新しいのもね、ね。
Oh, this feels nice, the new one too.
いや、今回はね、いろんなところにすごいこだわってて、ちょっとこのねサムネでもわかると思うんですけど、今ね、ちょっとリップつけてますリップ。
Well, this time I was really particular about various details. As you can see from the thumbnail, I'm putting on lipstick right now.
うん、うん、うん。いい感じリップ。
Yep, yep, yep. Nice lipstick.
チークとかもね、あ、アイラインとかアイシャドウもね、しっかりパパパパパパパパパパってね、つけていかないと、やっぱりね素敵な感じにね、しなきゃいけないからね。
Cheek makeup, eyeliner, and eyeshadow too—I gotta apply them properly, tap tap tap, so it turns out nicely.
ドキドキ。何が食べてるんじゃない、リップつけてる今リップリップ。
My heart is pounding. Not eating anything, I'm putting on lipstick right now.
リップってさ、やっぱさ、色合い一つでもさ、雰囲気変わるからさ。
Lipstick changes the vibe even with just one shade.
みんな、みんなにねメイクするところは見せるわけいかないからね、このサムネで今やってるから。
I can't show you guys where I do my makeup, so I'm doing it right now with this thumbnail.
ドキドキしてる。あ、ドキドキ!ドキドキ!ドキドキ!
My heart is pounding. Ah, pounding! Pounding!
美味しいじゃ、リップは、リップは食べませんから。
Delicious? No, you can't eat lipstick!
最初ね、ありがとうございます。爪もね、意識してるのそうなんですよ。ちょっとピンク系のねネイルをね。
Thank you first of all. I'm conscious of my nails too. I've got some pinkish nail polish.
私はね、あんまりこう、ピアノとかを弾くので爪伸ばせないんですけど、こういうね可愛いね、マニキュアぐらいだったらいいかなと思ってね、ちょっとねマニキュアにも挑戦しましたね。
I don't grow my nails out much since I play the piano and stuff, but I thought cute nail polish would be fine, so I tried out nail polish.
どうですか、みなさん?ゾワゾワのロボ子じゃありがとう。
How is it, everyone? Thanks, creepy Roboco.
なんで袖に注目もうそれ見えてるじゃん、これ衣装で。
Why focus on the sleeves? You can already see that with this outfit.
みんな、見て私を。
Everyone, look at me.
はーい、ということでじゃあ、見て!
Hii, so now, look!
私の新しいお化粧とちょっと変わった私のお衣装でーす!
My new makeup and slightly changed outfit!
やったー!
Yay!
おー、みんなどうかな?みんなどうかな?
Oh, how is everyone? How is everyone doing?
頑張ったんだよ!頑張ってさ、ほらアイラインとかもリップとかもちょっとね、綺麗にね塗っちゃいました。
I worked hard! I worked hard on the eyeliner and lipstick, applying them neatly.
いいでしょ?ど、どうかな、みんな?
Isn't it nice? How is it, everyone?
おお!おー、ありがとう、サンキュー!
Oh! Oh, thank you, thank you!
えらぽい、ありがとう。そしてね、
Good girl, thanks. And then,
まあもちろんお化粧が一番なんですけど、見てくださいよ、この衣装。
of course the makeup is number one, but please look at this outfit.
いろんな場所がね、ちょっとずつ変わってるんですよ。
Various parts are changing little by little.
例えば、このさ、襟のところ見て、ここさ元々まっしろだったんだけど、金のさフチがつくようになってたりとかさ、
For example, look at the collar here. Originally it was pure white, but now it has gold edges added, and stuff like that.
あ、ここにも金網だったものがあったりとか、あとここ
Ah, there are also things that used to be wire mesh here and there, and also here...
あ、ここ、星、星がついてる。そこにあるの
Ah, here, there are stars attached. That is there...
あ、ほら、ここここここここここここ、ほら、ここちょっとさ
Ah, look, here, here, here, look, here a bit...
ゴールドに換えてたりとか
changed to gold and stuff
ちょっと下の方見てもらうとね、こうフリフリするね、星がついたり、まあ全体的にね
If you look a bit towards the bottom, it flutters, has stars attached, well, overall...
ちょっと金、金をね、入れた感じにして、ちょっとだけね、衣装もね、豪華にマイナーチェンジしましたよ。
making it feel like it incorporates some gold, just slightly, the outfit too has been given a luxurious minor change.
どうですか？
How is it?
え、もう嬉しい、もうこれがさ、ステージショーみたいに豪華でさ、もうびっくりしちゃった。
Ah, I'm so happy, this is so luxurious like a stage show, I was so surprised.
これ、私普段使、普段使ってる衣装なんですかって思って、普段の衣装豪華すぎませんか？
Thinking, is this the outfit I usually use? Isn't my usual outfit too luxurious?
ってなってね、すごいね、バージョンが上がりました。ねえ、ゴージャスになってるね。
And so, wow, the version went up. Hey, it's become gorgeous.
じゃあ、みんな、素敵って思ってくれてるかな？
Well then, everyone, I wonder if you think it's wonderful?
思ってくれてない？
You don't think so?
思って、思ってよ！
Think so, think so!
ありがとう！みんなありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you everyone!
ちょっとね横からとかもね、移動しますね、横顔、ウインク。
Also from the side, I'll move, profile, wink.
これはすごい！
This is amazing!
すごいでしょう？すごいでしょう？もうさ、嬉しくってさ、嬉しくってさ、もう早くさ、みんなにさ
Isn't it amazing? I was so happy, so happy, I want to quickly, everyone...
新しいお化粧を見せたかったの。
show you my new makeup.
みんな！
Everyone!
今の私のスクリーンショットを撮って、新しい私をみんなに広めてほしいよ！
Please take screenshots of me right now and spread the new me to everyone!
なんかみんなしてほしいポーズとかある？してほしいポーズとかあったりしますか？
Are there any poses you want everyone to do? Are there any poses you'd like?
出そうか。えーっ、出そっ、出そっ、うん。
Shall I strike a pose? Uh, let's do it, let's do it, yeah.
なんでバームクーヘンって言ってんの？
Why are you saying Baumkuchen?
これじゃん。バームクーヘンこれじゃん。しかもこれ止まれないからスクリーンショットに向かないじゃん。
This is it. Baumkuchen is this. Plus, since this doesn't stop, it's not good for screenshots, right?
CDのジャケットのポーズ。どのCDのジャケット？
CD jacket pose. Which CD jacket?
これ、なんかどれだ？どのCDだ？ふふっ
This, like, which one? Which CD is it? Hehe.
なんでバームクーヘンで疑問形なのは？
Why are you asking with a question mark about Baumkuchen?
茶道ボクシング
Sado boxing.
ジャンプ！ジャンプ！
Jump! Jump!
謎のポーズ。で、反復横跳び。
Mysterious pose. And then, side-to-side hopping.
いや、これスクショできないでしょ、絶対。
No, you definitely can't take a screenshot of this.
バナナボート。
Banana boat.
バナナボート。よっこいしょ、よっこいしょ、よっこいしょ。
Banana boat. Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho.
バナナボート、バナナボート。
Banana boat, banana boat.
あ、切り抜きするから大丈夫。
Ah, I'll clip it, so it's fine.
みんなが言ってる船長のポーズっていうのがよくわからない。どういうポーズの事なんだろう？
I don't really understand what everyone calls the captain's pose. What kind of pose is that?
ズームにされた？ズームにされてた？
Were you zoomed in? Were you being zoomed in?
あ、インスタントヘヴンのポーズこれか？これか？
Ah, is this the Instant Heaven pose? Is it this?
ハッピーハッピーにゃんにゃんこれじゃん。
Happy Happy Nyan Nyan, this is it.
え、なんか、そう、こういう、こういう、いや、こここういうポーズしてるイメージしかないんだけど
Eh, like, yeah, like this, like this, no, I only have the image of doing this kind of pose here...
こっち側だよね。
It's this side, right?
さっき昨日のも客観だよ。
Earlier yesterday's was also from an observer's perspective.
あって る？合ってる？
Is it right? Is it right?
近かった
That was close.
髪の毛サラサラだよね
My hair is silky smooth, right?
そうだよ
That's right.
髪の毛もさ
My hair too...
そう、サラサラなの
Yeah, it's silky smooth.
あ、ベノムの目？
Ah, Venom's eye?
目
Eye.
ピース！ハッピーポーズ！
Peace! Happy pose!
えーい！ピース！
Hey! Peace!
どうかな？いい感じにみんな撮れたかな？
How is it? Did everyone get a good shot?
なに？まころんのと？
What? Makoron's...?
えーちゃんからサプライズプレゼントがあるって
Eh-chan said there's a surprise present...
え、なに？
Eh, what?
すごい！
Amazing!
これえーちゃんからの
This is from Eh-chan...
画像のプレゼントだって
...a photo present, she said.
手紙？
A letter?
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
え、全然知らなかったんだけど
Eh, I had no idea at all.
ソラへ、3周年おめでとう。
Dear Sora, Happy 3rd anniversary.
サプライズでスタッフさんにお願いして手紙とお手紙を渡していました。
As a surprise, I asked the staff to give you a letter and notes.
びっくりした？
Were you surprised?
びっくりしてくれるといいな。
I hope you were surprised.
ソラはいつもあんまりびっくりしないからさ。
Sora, you don't usually get surprised much, after all.
この写真は、お化粧が完成した時に撮った最初の写真です。
This photo was the very first one taken when my makeup was completed.
私はソラの少し照れて、恥ずかしがっているような、優しさが滲み出るような顔が好きで、写真集でもそれはきっと表れているけど、
I love Sora's slightly shy, embarrassed-looking expression that radiates kindness. It definitely shows in her photobook too, but...
これは私の趣味です。新しいお化粧をめると、ありがとう。
this is just my hobby. When I got the new makeup... thank you.
この1年、ソラは自分のやりたい方向を自分でいろいろ考えて、
Over this past year, Sora has thought about the direction she wants to go on her own,
私は私でホロライブで働いて、ホロライブの みんながどうアイドルできるかを考えるという、お互いに挑戦の1年だったと思います。
and I worked at Hololive, thinking about how everyone in Hololive can be idols. I think it was a year of challenges for both of us.
最初ゲリラで配信をすると聞いたテレビを見た時、すごくドキドキしました。
When I first saw on TV that you were going to do a guerrilla stream, my heart was racing so much.
スタジオでスタッフさんもいる中だったけど、私はとてもハラハラして見ていました。
Even though we were in the studio with the staff around, I was watching on edge with suspense.
でも、楽しくいろんな放送をしてるソラを見て、今は信じてよかったと思っています。
But seeing Sora doing various fun broadcasts, now I think I'm glad I believed in you.
自分から曲を作ったり、ホロライブのみんなに凸したりしているソラを見て、
Seeing Sora making her own songs and visiting everyone's streams in Hololive,
ほんの少しだけ寂しい気もするけど、それ以上にとても嬉しいです。
I feel just a tiny bit lonely, but more than that, I'm so happy.
私も私で安心して自分の仕事を頑張ろうと思います。
I also want to feel reassured and work hard on my own job.
ソラがみんながもっとアイドルできるように、夢に近づけるように、私も一人ひとりと裏方としていろいろ挑戦中です。
Sora, so that everyone can become better idols and get closer to their dreams, I'm also taking on various challenges behind the scenes with each and everyone.
また喜んでもらえるような嬉しいお知らせができるように、実は今も挑戦中です。お楽しみにね。
We're actually still in the middle of challenging ourselves so that we can bring you happy news that will make you smile again. Look forward to it.
3年目もこれからも一緒に頑張りましょう。これからも止まらずに進んで、
Let's do our best together in our 3rd year and beyond. Continuing to move forward without stopping,
少し疲れたらいつでも私に話してね。
if you ever get a little tired, talk to me anytime.
ざっと第一号、友人Aより
First, from Friend A...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
びっくりしたぁ。全然聞いてなかった、本当にきっぴ...
I was so surprised. I really had no idea...
やっぱ、お互い3年っていうね、長い時間だと思うんですけど、
I mean, three years for both of us is such a long time,
でも本当にあっというまに二人して、立場は違っても、一緒に歩いてきたなって、思います。
but I feel like time flew by, and even in different roles, we walked this path together.
本当にここまで頑張ってきて、こんなに素敵なメイクもできるようになって、
Working hard to get this far, and being able to wear such wonderful makeup...
本当にやってよかったなって思います。
I really feel so glad I did it.
えーちゃんも、オニールスタッフさんも、今ここで見てくれてる、
A-chan, the O-Neil staff, everyone watching right here,
そらとものみんなも、私にとって大切な宝物で、かけがえのないものです。
and all my Sora-tomo are such precious treasures, completely irreplaceable.
これからも、これからもみんなと一緒に、このライブのみんなと... みんなと一緒に、
From now on too, I hope to walk together with everyone, with everyone from this live...
歩いて行けたら、幸せだな、って思います。
and be truly happy.
本当に3周年、お祝いしてくれて、ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for celebrating my 3rd anniversary.
はぁ、びっくりしたぁ！
Phew, I was so surprised!
本当に聞いてなかったよぉ。
I really had no idea.
私たちホロライブプロダクションはまだまだ、発展途上です。
We in Hololive Production are still developing.
色々あります。でも、これからもホロライブプロダクションみんなで、そして、応援してくださってる、
There are all sorts of things. But from now on too, all of us in Hololive, and everyone supporting us,
皆さんと一緒に、成長していきたいです。
I want to grow together with all of you.
一緒に大きい夢をいっぱい見ていきましょう。
Let's dream big dreams together.
皆さん今日はどうでしたか？
How was today, everyone?
すごい、私にとってはサプライズがあって、とってもびっくりしたんですけども、
It was amazing, there was a surprise for me, and I was so surprised,
本当にね、素敵なみんなに囲まれて、なんか、恵まれている環境でこう活動してこれてるなって思ってます。
but being surrounded by wonderful people in such a blessed environment, I feel truly grateful to keep going.
せっかくこんなに楽しい日に、最後は歌わなきゃもったいないでしょう！
On such a fun day, it'd be a waste not to sing at the end!
ということで、最後に1曲、私の自己紹介ソングといえばこれっていう曲をね、歌って... ぴきき、ありがとうございます！
So, for the very last song, singing what is basically my self-introduction song... Phew, thank you!
それでは、最後は盛り上がって、終わりにしましょう！
Well then, let's get hyped and bring it to an end!
聞いてください、Dream☆Story！
Please listen to 'Dream☆Story'!
最後はみんな盛り上がるよ！
Let's all get hyped at the end!
せーの、いっくよー！ はいっ、はいっ、はいっ、はいっ、はいっ！
Ready, here we go! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
今日は皆さん、私の3周年をお祝いしてくれて、ありがとうございます！
Everyone today, thank you so much for celebrating my 3rd anniversary!
こと 忘れてしまいたくなる
I want to forget about things like...
昨日のあの記憶のピースね
Those puzzle pieces of yesterday's memories,
なくしたりはできそうもないけど
it doesn't seem like I could ever lose them,
上手く繋げばまだ続きへ
but if I connect them well, it continues further.
でも今は関係ないんだよ
But none of that matters right now!
そんなことも忘れちゃえるような
Into a strange world where we can forget
不思議な世界にアクセス全開で飛び込もう一緒さ
all about that with full access, let's dive in together!
でもでも急ぎ足しはきみも連れ去ってしまうから
But rushing might sweep you away too,
まあ待ってるでしょ大丈夫だからたまにはゆっくり日のお休みにしたら
so wait, it's fine. Sometimes, let's take a relaxing day off!
それじゃあ早めのリズムで
Well then, with a quicker rhythm,
みんな行くよ！
everyone, here we go!
止まねえぞ！ 飛んでけー！
We won't stop! Fly away!
大きく息を吸ったら 僕らの
Taking a deep breath, our
ストーリーがいま フレグランスより
story right now, more than a fragrance,
もっともっと遠くへ
goes further and further away.
最初が肝心なんです 初めまして こんにちは せーので
The beginning is crucial. Nice to meet you, hello, on three:
ときのそらだよ！ おもしろい？ ふざけちゃおう！
It's Tokino Sora! Is it fun? Let's mess around!
フラット生まれ とどけ ドキドキして 外側には見えない二人や
Born flat, let it reach, heart pounding, two people unseen from outside
瞬きも捨てられない
We can't even afford to blink.
あぁ、そらね最高でしょ？ イエーイ！
Ah, Sora is the best, right? Yay!
いい事進めば また後ろへ
Whenever good things progress, it goes backward again
見えない力から邪魔されている
interfered with by an unseen force.
ジャンプしたりできたらいいけれど
It would be nice if we could jump,
それも愛嬌ということでよろしく
but consider that part of my charm, please!
でも今は関係ないんだよ
But none of that matters right now!
心響くリズムを辿れば
If we follow the heart-resonating rhythm,
不思議な世界への続きのページで また出逢えますように
may we meet again on the next page to a strange world.
文字の小説めのテンポもいいけど 今はそんな場合じゃない
The tempo of a text novel is nice, but this isn't the time for that!
じゃない！ だけど大丈夫、ひといき続けたのなら
It's not! But it's alright, if we keep catching our breath,
最初のサインの合図で 飛んでけー！
at the signal of the first sign, fly away!
大きな声で叫んだら 僕らの
If we shout with a loud voice, our
ストーリーがいま 紡がれてく もっともっと遠くへ
story is now being spun, further and further away,
ボリュームはマックスで
with maximum volume!
初めまして こんにちは せーので
Nice to meet you, hello, on three:
ときのそらだよ！ おもしろい？ ふざけちゃおう！
It's Tokino Sora! Is it fun? Let's mess around!
フラット生まれ響け はちゃめちゃだって もっと初めてにめざめたんだ デカいストーリーやっぱ 一秒たりとも目を離さないでほしいな 瞬きも捨てられない
Born flat, let it echo, even if it's crazy, awakened to something brand new. A big story after all—I want you never to take your eyes off me for even a second, not even blinking!
あぁ、そらね最高じゃない？ イエーイ！
Ah, isn't Sora the best? Yay!
ねぇねぇテンション 高まってテンション
Hey hey tension, rising tension,
ワクワクゲームは 何やかんやで 誰も止められないよ
this exciting game, no matter what, nobody can stop it!
みんな 今日は ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for today!
大きく息を吸ったら 僕らのストーリーがいま フレグランスより もっともっと遠くへ
Taking a deep breath, our story right now, more than a fragrance, goes further and further away.
最初がかんじんなんです これからも どうぞよろしくね
The beginning is crucial. Thank you for your continued support!
せーので ときのそらだよ！
On three, it's Tokino Sora!
おもしろい？ ふざけちゃおう！
Is it fun? Let's mess around!
フラット生まれ響け はちゃめちゃだって もっと初めてにめざめたんだ デカいストーリーやっぱ 一秒たりとも目を離さないでほしいな 瞬きも捨てられない
Born flat, let it echo, even if it's crazy, awakened to something brand new. A big story after all—I want you never to take your eyes off me for even a second, not even blinking!
あぁ、そらね最高でしょ？ イエーイ！
Ah, Sora is the best, right? Yay!
みんな、今日はありがとうございましたー！
Everyone, thank you so much for today!